for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
The New Akatsuki
Everyone is growing weary
of fighting.
（長門）みんな戦いに
疲れてきてるね。
Yes...
（弥彦）あぁ。
Even if we win,
戦いに勝ったって
暁には報酬も何もねえ。
the Akatsuki doesn't receive
any rewards...
The only things we have
are our ideals.
あるのは　ただ理想だけ。
In time, pent-up weariness
will erase that ideal.
いつか　たまった疲労は
その理想を消してくだろうよ。
Are you saying that everyone will
soon forget what they're fighting for?
みんな何のために戦ってるのか
それを忘れるっていうのか？
Nagato...
長門　お前が暁のリーダーに
なってくれないか？
Will you become the leader
of the Akatsuki?
Huh?
え？
俺は　リーダーなんて器じゃねえんだ。
I'm not... cut out to be a leader.
That day...
あのとき…。
I killed someone for the first time.
初めて人を刺した。
The feeling of that moment
hasn't left these hands.
その感触がこの手に残ってて→
And I can't stop trembling!
俺は　それだけでブルッてる。
Yahiko...
弥彦…。
But you're different.
だけど　お前は違う。
You have the mark of a hero...
お前には英雄の印がある。
A special symbol known
as the Rinnegan...
輪廻眼という特別な印が。
that will become
everyone's new ideal.
それが
みんなの新しい理想となる。
Yahiko!
弥彦　俺の輪廻眼を利用するのか？
Are you going to take advantage
of my Rinnegan?
俺は自分が怖いんだ。
I'm scared of myself.
I've suffered so long because
of these eyes.
ずっと　この眼のせいで
苦しんできた。
I know...
わかってる。
But you have someone who can
keep that power in check for you.
だがお前には
その力を制御する存在がいる。
Konan will always be at your side.
小南は　ずっと　お前のそばにいる。
Yahiko...
弥彦…。
（鳩助）兄貴　大変だ！
どうした？
Hey, Brother! Big news!
What's going on?
A messenger from Hanzo is here.
半蔵の使者が来た。
Are you Yahiko,
the leader of the Akatsuki?
（勘蔵）そなたが暁のリーダー
弥彦殿か？
Yes, I am.
あぁ　そうだ。
I am Kanzo, a trusted friend
of Hanzo of the Salamander.
拙者は　山椒魚の半蔵の腹心
勘蔵と申す。
I've heard many rumors
about you Akatsuki...
そなたたち　暁の噂は
かねがね聞いておる。
How you seek peace without
relying on military weapons.
武力に頼らぬ
平和主義を貫いているとか。
That is the Akatsuki's founding principle.
それが俺たち暁の理念だ。
Hanzo asked me to deliver
a confidential letter to you.
半蔵より
親書を預かってまいりました。
Please...
これを。
これは本当なのか？
Is he serious?
He would like to
meet you personally.
そなたらと
じかにお会いしたいと。
Hanzo has given the Akatsuki
his seal of approval.
半蔵は　暁をお認めになった。
In time...
（勘蔵）いずれ半蔵は
そなたたちに→
Hanzo will leave you to handle
the peace negotiations
雨隠れを囲む三国の和平交渉を
任せるつもりでもいる。
between the three nations
that surround the Hidden Rain.
Handle the negotiations
between the three nations...?
（鳩助）三国の交渉役って
すげぇぜ　兄貴！
That's amazing, Brother!
この話　承知したと
半蔵様に伝えてくれ。
Please relay to Lord Hanzo
that I accept.
（みんな）うぉ～っ！
That means we can help people
out in the open!
（鳩助）これで俺たちも
堂々と人助けができる！
So many gave their lives
for us to get to this point.
ここに来るまで
多くの犠牲を払ってきた。
Finally, we'll be able to
face them with pride.
やっと　その連中に
顔向けができる。
Yahiko, your determination to free others
from pain reached Hanzo.
弥彦　キミの相手の痛みを
わかろうとする思いが→
半蔵に届いたんだよ。
Look...
見てごらんよ。
暁は理想を取り戻した。
The Akatsuki's ideals
have been restored.
There was never a need
for a symbol.
印なんて必要なかったんだよ。
We'll all follow your dream,
no matter where that leads us.
みんな　キミの理想に
どこまでもついていく。
Nagato...
長門…。
俺たちは間違ってなかった。
We weren't wrong!
明日の半蔵様との会合は
俺と長門で行く。
Nagato and I will go to
the meeting tomorrow with Lord Hanzo.
Are you sure, Brother?
We'll all go with you...
大丈夫かよ　兄貴
俺たちも一緒に…。
No, that's not necessary.
いや　大丈夫だ。
俺たちが大挙して→
Lord Hanzo will be shocked if
too many of us show up.
押しかけたら
半蔵様も　ビックリしちまう。
I know, but...
確かに　そうだけど。
By the way, where's Konan?
そういえば小南は？
She went to patrol
the Seventh Ward.
急きょ第七地区の
見回りに行ってる。
She won't be back until
tomorrow morning.
明日の朝まで帰らない。
I see... On such a special day too.
そうか　せっかくの日なのに。
Anyway... Today, the Akatsuki took
a giant step forward!
とにかく暁は今日
大きな一歩を記した！
Everyone! Set aside your duties
for today and celebrate!
みんな　今日は
任務を忘れ　無礼講だ！
（みんな）お～っ！
The Akatsuki brats aren't suspicious
at all, are they?
（半蔵）暁の小僧たちには
気づかれてはいまいな？
Of course not.
（ダンゾウ）もちろんだ。
If the one called Yahiko is killed,
the Akatsuki will naturally die off.
弥彦とかいう小僧が死ねば
暁は自然消滅するだろう。
And what of your plans?
そちらの首尾は？
No need to worry.
心配無用。
（小南）誰が？
Who could have...?
This is...!
（小南）これは！
We should be securing
the hostage right about now.
（半蔵）今頃　人質を
確保している頃だ。
With this, that lawless gang that
threatens the village will disappear,
これで里を脅かす
不逞の輩は消え→
and the Hidden Rain will be yours.
雨隠れは貴殿のものだ。
We finally made it up to this point.
やっと　ここまで来た。
Nagato.
長門。
You're—!
お前は！？
Reality is moving ahead quickly.
現実が大きく動き出している。
Cut your ties with Yahiko immediately
and join me.
今すぐ弥彦たちと手を切り
俺と行動をともにしろ。
Otherwise, you will all...
でなければ　お前たちは…。
We will what?
俺たちが何だ！？
What Yahiko speaks of
are just ideals.
弥彦の言っていることは
ただの理想だ。
He tries to understand others' pain...
相手の痛みをわかろうと→
but they do not even attempt
to know our pain.
相手は　こっちの痛みなど
知ろうとはしない。
Furthermore, this world has
no desire for that either.
そして　この世界もまた
そんなことを望んでいない。
That is reality.
それが現実だ。
輪廻眼を持つお前なら
それを理解できるはずだ。
You possess the Rinnegan,
so you should understand.
アンタが何を言おうと
俺は弥彦の理想を信じる！
No matter what you say,
I believe in Yahiko's ideals!
I guess without pain...
you cannot experience reality.
痛みが伴わなければ
現実を実感できんか？
In that respect, even though
you possess the Rinnegan,
そういうところは
輪廻眼を持とうと→
you still think like
an average person.
お前も凡人だな　長門。
よかろう　真実を見極めろ。
自らの痛みとともにな。
Very well...
Go see reality for yourself,
and experience pain.
There you are, Nagato.
ここにいたのか　長門。
弥彦。
Yahiko...
Was someone just here?
誰かいたのか？
No...
いや…。
Let's get going.
そろそろ出発しよう。
Or we'll be late for the meeting
with Lord Hanzo.
半蔵様との会合に遅れちまう。
うん　行こう！
Right, let's go!
Oww!
イテェ！　何だよ　人が気持よく
寝てるってのに　まったく！
What's the big idea?
I was having a nice nap!
なになに？
What?
Hey! Where'd Brothers Yahiko
and Nagato go?!
おい　弥彦と長門の兄貴は！？
I think they left already.
もう　出かけたんじゃないのか？
The meeting with Hanzo is today.
今日は半蔵との…。
Wake the guys up!
We have to catch up with them!
みんなを叩き起こせ！
兄貴たちのあとを追うぞ！
What's wrong?
I'll tell you later!
どうした！？
わけはあとで話す！
おい　いったい何があった！？
What's going on anyway?
We just received word
木ノ葉国境付近にいる→
from a member of
the Hidden Leaf border team.
メンバーから連絡が入った。
The Leaf's ANBU Black Ops are
on their way to Hanzo's as well.
木ノ葉の暗部の部隊が→
半蔵の元に向かったってな！
The Leaf's ANBU?
えっ　木ノ葉の暗部？
Why are they going to Hanzo's?
なんで連中が半蔵のとこに？
詳しいことは　わからねえ！
I don't know the specifics.
だが　イヤなタイミングじゃねえかよ。
But I just don't like the timing
of it all, you know?
And when you think about it...
それに　よく考えてみりゃ→
this thing with Hanzo just sounds
too good to be true.
半蔵の話ってのも→
うますぎる気がする！
Then that means...
today's meeting with Hanzo is...
それじゃ　今日の半蔵との会合…。
Whatever it is,
we need to let Brothers know!
とにかく兄貴たちの
耳に入れておかねえと！
As much as I regret it,
I can't let you go any further.
残念だが　ここから先に
お前たちを通すわけにはいかん。
Who are you?!
誰だ！？
My name is Madara Uchiha...
俺の名は　うちはマダラ。
Damn you! Did Hanzo send you?
キサマ　半蔵の差し金か！？
I don't work for Hanzo.
半蔵の仲間ではないが→
But I can't let you interfere right now.
今　お前たちによけいな
手出しをされては困る。
I want Nagato to see
what reality is.
俺は長門に現実を知って
もらわなきゃならないんでな。
We don't have time for
your nonsense.
何のことかわかんねえが
時間がねえ！
Kill them!
コイツを叩きのめせ！
（みんな）おお～っ！
You take care of the weaklings.
ザコは任せた。
You sure like to order me around!
（ゼツ）まったく
人使いが荒いんだから。
I'm Kyusuke the Swift!
Don't underestimate my speed!
韋駄天の鳩助！
俺の足を
なめてもらっちゃ困るぜ！
うお～！
I slipped right through him?
すり抜けた。
いったいどうなって…。
What's going on?!
Kyusuke!
鳩助！
You bastards!
テメエら　なんで　こんな　ことを…。
Why... are you... doing this?
I'm going to awaken Nagato's Rinnegan
in the truest sense possible.
長門の輪廻眼を
本当の意味で開眼させる。
What're you talking about?
なんのことだ？
There is no such thing as peace
in this accursed world.
この呪われた世界に
本当の平和など存在しない。
Nagato must abandon this dream
and set out into a new world.
長門は今の理想を捨て
新たな世界に旅立つ。
I'm not going to let you!
そうはいくかよ！
Daibutsu!
大仏　俺ごとやれ！
Now! Go right through me!
ぐっ…。
Hurry!
早く！
I'll see you in the next world!
あの世で会おうぞ！
はっ！
The Water Prison Jutsu?
水牢の術か。
この程度の術で　俺はやれんぞ。
You can't beat me with a jutsu like this!
This is no ordinary Water Prison.
《ただの水牢じゃねえ》
This is cement!
《これはセメント》
For the first time in
my dismal life as a war orphan...
《戦争孤児だった俺の
やさぐれた人生の中で→
I found hope in the Akatsuki!
暁は初めて見た希望だったんだ。
You think... I'd let some bastard
like you take that away?!
それを　テメエなんかに奪われて
たまるかよ！》
He's sacrificing his life
in this attack...
《捨て身の攻撃なのだろうが→
But, as expected,
we're literally in different dimensions.
お前とでは
文字どおり次元が違う》
No way!
そんな…。
Kyusuke...
鳩助　お前の死はムダには…。
Your death will not be...
Owww...
イタタタ…　固まった表皮が
剥けちゃって　ヒリヒリするよ。
The outer skin hardened...
and peeled off, and it stings!
Sorry, but this is the end for all of you.
悪いが　お前たちは全員
ここで始末する。
Are you okay?
大丈夫か？
ああ。
Yeah.
Come, we have to hurry!
さあ　急ぐぞ。
長門の運命を見届ける。
We have to witness Nagato's destiny!
Yahiko...
（半蔵）弥彦。　リーダーのお前には
ここで死んでもらう。
You are the leader,
so you must die.
If you resist, this woman will die.
抵抗すれば　この女の命はない。
You! The red-haired one.
そこの赤い髪のお前
それで弥彦を殺せ。
Use that to kill Yahiko.
Then I will spare you and the woman.
そうすれば
女とお前は助けてやる。
Don't, Nagato!
やめて長門。　私のことはいいから
２人ともここから逃げて！
Never mind me!
Both of you escape!
Nagato.
（弥彦）長門。
Kill me.
俺を殺れ。
Nagato!
長門！
やめて！
No!
Hurry it up.
早くしろ。
この女が死んでもいいのか？
Or do you want this woman to die?!
Konan...
小南…。
Yahi—
弥彦…。
You and Konan... must survive,
no matter what it takes.
小南と　なんとしてでも
生き延びろ。
You are...
お前は　この世の救世主だ。
the savior... of this world.
I know... you can...
お前だったら　本当に…。
do it.
Yahiko!
弥彦！
Kill them!
やれ！
He repelled it!
弾いただと！？
どうやって？
How?!
Did we get him?
やったか。
Nagato...
長門。
小南。
Konan, hold onto Yahiko
and stay still.
弥彦を抱いて　じっとしていろ。
Not bad, kid!
やるな　小僧。
You escaped even while being hit
by my Fire Style Jutsu!
わしの火遁を食らいながら
逃げきるとは。
You're... no ordinary kid.
お前　ただのガキではないな
その眼。
Those eyes...
Get him!
やれ！
Summoning Jutsu!
口寄せ　外道魔像！
Gedo Statue!
（みんな）ぐわぁ～！
There it is!
おっ　出た！
呼んだか。
So he summoned it.
It's the Ten Tails' husk...
十尾の抜け殻。
What... is that?!
なんだ　あれは。
Nagato... No! Don't use that!
長門　これは使っちゃダメ！
うおぉ～！！
ぐわぁ！
We're dead if that touches us!
あれに触れたら死ぬぞ！
うわぁ！
うおぉ～！！
So you were the leader
behind the scenes.
お前が　カゲのリーダーだったようだな。
It's quite a surprise that
you possess the Rinnegan.
輪廻眼を持っていようとは
驚かされたわ。
Nagato...
長門…。
うおぉ～！！
Teleportation Jutsu!
瞬身の術！
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
Nagato, Yahiko, Konan...
長門　弥彦　小南。
The world of dreams...
夢の世界　そこで
また会わせてやる　必ず。
I shall let you see each other there...
without fail.
Didn't I say so?
俺の言ったとおりだったろ。
Yeah, I finally understand.
（長門）ああ　やっとわかったよ。
The selfish desire to
preserve peace causes war.
平和を保ちたいとする
利己的な意思が戦争を起こし→
Hatred is born from wanting
to protect love.
愛を守るために
憎しみが生まれる。
There's no such thing as peace
in this accursed world.
この呪われた世界に
本当の平和など存在しない。
Exactly.
そのとおりだ。
You will always be the leader
of the Akatsuki...
暁は　永遠にキミがリーダーだ。
弥彦。
Yahiko.
I already know
wakatten da yo
it doesn't belong to anyone else
hoka no dare demo nakute
I'll follow all the rainbows in the sky
kono sora ippai no niji wo kakete miseru yo
now matter how much time passes I can never reach it
itsumade tattemo todokanai yo
I keep repeating the same thing every day
ato nankai mo kurikaesu nichijou
I'm chasing a future I once dreamed of
oikaketeru no wa itsuka jibun de egaita mirai
and I was blaming it all on someone else
mata dareka no sei ni shiteta
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I can't go on like this
kono mama ja dame na koto
can I even believe in the "future self" I saw with my own eyes anymore?
kono me de midashita ashita no jibun wa mou shinjite ii n desu ka
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I have to go
ikanakucha ikenai koto
beyond the rainbow there's another future waiting for me
niji no mukou de matteru mou hitotsu no mirai he
Hey, Kakashi!
What's all the fuss?
They're about to announce
the Fourth Hokage!
Don't be surprised!
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
The Fourth Hokage is going to
be Minato Sensei!
Rin, it seems like Minato Sensei
is going to be Hokage!
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
If he's the Hokage,
I'm sure Sensei will...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"A Mask That Hides the Heart"
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート　名曲！
にっぽんの歌』　２時間スペシャル。
... prevent any more victims like you guys...
（松丸）今回も
豪華な歌手の皆さんによる→